Guide to the Department of Astronomy, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Department of Astronomy, Yale University, records
1848-1979
RU 274
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
67.75
(176 boxes)
The records consist of correspondence, observation books, memoranda, and research notes documenting the activities and operations of the Yale Department of Astronomy. Included are subject files maintained by the directors of the Yale Observatory.
Yale University. Department of Astronomy
Brouwer, Dirk, 1902-
Brown, Ernest W. (Ernest William), 1866-1938
Elkin, William L. (William Lewis), 1855-1933
Newton, H. A. (Hubert Anson), 1830-1896
Schlesinger, Frank, 1871-1943
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 14-B (YRG 14-B), Records of academic departments and programs of the Yale Faculty of Arts and Sciences.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Existence and Location of Copies
The papers of Frank Schlesinger from both Yale University and the University of Pittsburgh are available on microfilm (Film MISC 978).
Arrangement
The records are arranged as follows: I. Hubert Anson Newton, ca. 1860-1929. II. William Lewis Elkin, ca. 1883-1935. III. Ernest William Brown, 1880-1939. IV. Frank Schlesinger, 1915-1952. V. Dirk Brouwer, 1939-1967. VI. Astronomical Journal, 1941-1969. VII. Association of Universities for Research in Astronomy (AURA), 1965-1972. VIII. Research Data, 1874-1962. IX. Financial Records, 1882-1959; and subsequent accessions.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of correspondence, observation books, memoranda, and research notes documenting the activities and operations of the Yale Department of Astronomy. Included are subject files maintained by the directors of the Yale Observatory.
Astronomical observatories; Astronomy -- Research; Astronomy -- Study and teaching; Observatories; Universities and colleges -- Administration; Universities and colleges -- Departments; Astronomers; Association of Universities for Research in Astronomy; Yale University -- Administration; Yale University -- Curricula; Yale University -- Faculty; Yale University -- Finance; Yale University. Department of Astronomy; Yale University. Observatory
- Records, 1860-1972; Accession 1977-A-001
  Conditions Governing Access
  The materials are open for research.
  - I. Hubert Anson Newton, 1800's-1929
    - Correspondence
      - 1860-1865 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - 1866 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - 1867 (Box 1, Folder 3-4)
      - 1868 (Box 1, Folder 5-7)
      - 1869 (Box 1, Folder 8-9)
      - 1870 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - 1880-1886 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - 1890-1894 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - 1895-1896 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Business letters - meteorites, A-M, 1875-1895 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Business letters - meteorites, N-Z, 1882-1895 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Letter to Newton's daughter inquiring about his correspondence with Adolphe Quetelet., 1929 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Index [Catalog - shooting stars and allied subjects] (Box 2, Folder 18)
      - [1] 1866 Nov Meteors; Smithsonian tracks (Box 2, Folder 19)
      - [2] Detonating meteors (Box 2, Folder 20)
      - [3] 1866 Mar 27 (Box 2, Folder 21)
      - [4] 1894 Dec 15 (Box 2, Folder 22)
      - [5] 1893 Jan 13 (Box 2, Folder 23)
      - [6] 1893 Dec 20 (Box 2, Folder 24)
      - [7] Meteors on the morning of Saturday, 1868 November 14 (Box 3, Folder 25)
      - [8, 9] Newspaper articles on meteor observations, 1860 (Box 3, Folder 26)
      - [10] Draft of discussion of observation of meteors giving their path, 1492-1805 (Box 4, Folder 27)
      - [11] 1511 Sep 4 Crema, Italy - stonefall represented in Madonna di Foligno. (Box 4, Folder 28)
      - [12] 1868 Nov 13-14 meteor records (Box 4, Folder 29)
      - [13] 1875 Feb 12 mem. by Irish; mem. by Leonard (Box 4, Folder 30)
      - [14] 1887 Sep 15 (Box 4, Folder 31)
      - [15] 1821 Jun 21 (Box 4, Folder 32)
      - [16] 1869 May 5 (Box 4, Folder 33)
      - [17] 1869 Jan 1; 1876 Jun 28; 1884 May 20 (Box 4, Folder 34)
      - [18] 1864 May 14 (Box 4, Folder 35)
      - [19] 1868 Feb 29; 1883 Feb 16 (Box 4, Folder 36)
      - [20] 1808 Sep 3; 1868 Jan 30 (Box 4, Folder 37)
      - [21] Stonefalls, 1492 - 1815 [missing as of 2008 Apr 9] (Box 4, Folder 38)
      - [22] Stonefalls, 1819 Jun 13 - 1851 Nov 5 (Box 4, Folder 39)
      - [23] Detonating meteors, 1676 Mar 31 - 1889 May 8 (Box 4, Folder 40)
      - [24] Stonefalls, 1852 Dec 2 - 1868 Oct 1 (Box 4, Folder 41)
      - [25] Stonefalls, 1868 Sep 7 - 1885 Nov 27 (Box 4, Folder 42)
      - [26] 1886 Sep 6 in N. Hamp. and Vt., USA (Box 4, Folder 43)
      - [27] 1856 Aug 17 (Box 4, Folder 44)
      - [28] 1886 Aug, Sep 9, Sep 14, Nov 4 (Box 4, Folder 45)
      - [29] Directions for observers [folder empty] (Box 4, Folder 46)
      - [30] 1848 May 20, Cartine, ME., USA (Box 4, Folder 47)
      - [31] 1814 Sep 5 - Agen. (Box 4, Folder 48)
      - [32] List of American meteorites - 1828 Jun 4; 1839 Feb 13; 1859 Aug 11 (Box 4, Folder 49)
      - [33] 1788 Oct - 1895 Aug; paper on Biela meteors (Box 4, Folder 50)
      - [34] 1788 Oct 17 - 1896 May 7 (Box 4, Folder 51)
      - [35] 1812 Apr 10 (Box 4, Folder 52)
      - [36] 1878 Jul 15; 1882 Aug 2 (Box 4, Folder 53)
      - [37] 1838 Jul 22; 1859 May; 1871 spring; 1874 May 20 (Box 4, Folder 54)
      - [38] 1877 May 17 (Box 4, Folder 55)
      - [39] 1820 Jul 12; 1840 May 9 (Box 4, Folder 56)
      - [40] 1492 Nov 7; 1751 May 26 (Box 4, Folder 57)
      - [41] 1850 Nov 30 (Box 4, Folder 58)
      - [42] 1803 Apr 26; 1803 Oct 8; 1810 Nov 23; 1815 Oct 3; 1831 May 13 (July 18) (Box 4, Folder 59)
      - [43] Etoiles filantes (mem.) Haidinger 1863 Aug (mem.) Quetelet 1872 Jul 23 (Box 4, Folder 60)
      - [44] 1889 Jan 25 (Box 4, Folder 61)
      - [45] 1883 Feb 27 (Box 4, Folder 62)
      - [46] 1894 Jul 27 (Box 4, Folder 63)
      - [47] 1822 Mar 9; 1837 Dec 14; 1838 May 18 (Box 4, Folder 64)
      - [48] 1807 Dec 14 (Box 4, Folder 65)
      - [49] 1837 Dec 14; 1845 Aug 25 (Box 4, Folder 66)
      - [50] 1890 May 2 (Box 5, Folder 67)
      - [51] 1887 Jan 3 (Box 5, Folder 68)
      - [52] 1888 Aug 22 (19)? (Box 5, Folder 69)
      - [53] 1885 Nov 27 (Box 5, Folder 70)
      - [54] 1892 Aug 29 (Box 5, Folder 71)
      - [55] 1889 Feb 7 (Box 5, Folder 72)
      - [56] 1891 Feb 23 (Box 5, Folder 73)
      - [57] 1893 Aug 9 (Box 5, Folder 74)
      - [58] 1894 Jan 20 (Box 5, Folder 75)
      - [59] Iowa meteorite controversy, 1890 May 2 (Box 6, Folder 76-77)
      - [60] List of meteors (Box 6, Folder 78-79)
      - [61] 1861 Nov 13; 1863 Aug 8-9, 9-10, 10-11; 1864 Aug (Box 6, Folder 80)
      - [62] 1879 May 10 (Box 6, Folder 81)
      - [63] 1887 Nov 29; 1889 Dec 1; 1892 Jul 29; 1894 May 27; 1894 Aug 9-11; 1895 Jul 25 (Box 6, Folder 82)
      - [64] 1832 Nov 24; 1846 Jul 13; 1859 Aug 17; 1860 Aug 2; 1861 Jan 11; 1865 Jul 20 (Box 6, Folder 83)
      - [65,66,67] Meteor records, 1863-1867 (Box 6, Folder 84)
      - [68] 1876 Dec 19; 1876 Dec 21; 1877 Jan 23 (Box 6, Folder 85-86)
      - [69] Meteor observations, 1863-1876 (Box 7, Folder 87)
      - [70] Meteor observations, 1833-1896 (Box 7, Folder 88)
      - [71, 72] Meteor observations, 1676 Mar 31 - 1886 Nov 28 (Box 8, Folder 89)
      - [73] Meteor observations 1807 Dec 14 - 1894 Dec 15 (Box 9, Folder 90)
      - [74] Meteor observations 1889 Jul-Aug (Box 9, Folder 91-92)
      - [76] Letters about meteors - 1764 Jul 20; 1807 Dec 14; 1858-1868; 1867 Nov Ms. (Box 9, Folder 93-94)
      - [77] Meteor path determination introduction (Box 9, Folder 95)
      - [78] Biela's comet, 1872 Nov 24-30 (Box 9, Folder 96)
      - [79] Meteor observations 1676-1893 (Box 10, Folder 97)
      - [80] Dates of (suspected) detonating meteors AD34-1893 (Box 11, Folder 98)
      - [81] November meteors, discussion (clipping dated Nov 1892) (Box 11, Folder 99)
      - [82] Letters on observation of meteors, 1788, 1807, 1829, 1837, 1860-1896 (Box 11, Folder 100)
      - [83] 1807 Dec 14 Misc. Disc. and Comp. undated (Box 11, Folder 101)
      - [84] Miscellaneous memoranda (Box 11, Folder 102)
      - [85] References to Working Book (No, 79); Ref. to book p.35 not found (Box 11, Folder 103)
      - [86] References (Box 11, Folder 104)
      - [87] Undated meteors - Comp. (Box 11, Folder 105)
      - [88] Miscellaneous computations (Box 12, Folder 106)
      - [89] Miscellaneous not specific meteors (Box 12, Folder 107)
      - [90] Suggestions for observing meteors (Box 12, Folder 108)
      - [91] Meteors without certain date (Box 12, Folder 109)
      - [92] Miscellaneous - articles and discussions (Box 12, Folder 110)
      - [93] Capture of comets (Box 12, Folder 111-112)
      - Observations of (detonating?) meteors, 1676-1861. Presented by the family of the late Professor H.A. Newton, 1914. (Box 12, Folder 113)
      - Meteors: Jul 18, 1889 (Box 12, Folder 114)
      - Shooting stars: Jul 18, 1889 (Box 12, Folder 115)
      - Shooting stars: Jul 25, 1889 (Box 12, Folder 116)
      - H.A. Newton articles: "The Biela Meteors of Nov 27, 1885"; "Fireball of Jan 13, 1893"; "On the effect upon the earth's velocity produced by small bodies passing near the earth." (Box 12, Folder 117)
      - ["May be a piece of glass from the old Laboratory which was in existence from 1782-1888 on the Old Campus. This is similar to a piece of the Yale fence, a brick from Brick Row, etc. Checked by Dorrit Hoffleit, Astronomy Dept, 12/83"] (Box 12, Folder 118)
      - Information about collection: memo on papers of H.A. Newton. (Box 12, Folder 119)
      - Notes on meteors, 1583-1893 (Box 13, Folder 120)
    - Two short biographies of Newton by his niece, Maria Williams, and J.W. Gibbs (Box 13, Folder 121)
  - II. William Lewis Elkin, 1883-1935
    - Correspondence
      - From Sir David and Lady Gill, 1883-1890 (Box 14, Folder 1)
      - To Sir David Gill, 1884-1895 (Box 14, Folder 2)
      - Miscellaneous, 1912-1935 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Manuscripts
      - Report on the progress of photographing, 1894(?) (Box 14, Folder 4)
      - "The Velocity of Meteors as deduced from photographs at the Yale Observatory", undated (Box 14, Folder 5)
      - undated (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Manuscript and reprint, "Results of the Photographic Observations of the Leonids, November 14-15, 1898, at the Yale Observatory" (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Reprint, "On the Relative Refrangibility of the light of Mars and Stars" Astronomical Journal X no. 13, 1890 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Research notes
      - 1898-1905 (Box 14, Folder 9)
      - Transit Factors A and B for l=41° 19.'4 (Box 14, Folder 10)
      - Heliometer Observations of Cluster 4681 HGC, 1900-1901 (Box 14, Folder 11)
      - Star places and Heliometer Settings of Cluster 4681 HGG Triangulation (Box 14, Folder 12)
      - Aberration Tables (Box 14, Folder 13)
      - Tables of: zenith distance (to 75° only) (Box 14, Folder 14)
      - Tables of: q paralactic angle (Box 14, Folder 14)
      - Tables of: a azimith (for latitude 41° .32) (Box 14, Folder 14)
      - Emker Tables for Long. and Lat. into Right Ascension and Declination and vice versa - for E=23°27' (Box 14, Folder 15)
      - Division Errors of Scales, 1888 (Box 14, Folder 16)
      - Investigation of Micrometer Screw (Box 14, Folder 17)
      - Heliometer Obs. for Screw Error (Box 14, Folder 18)
      - Position Circle, 1886 (Box 14, Folder 19)
      - 1909 (Box 14, Folder 20)
      - Perseids, 1875-1899 (Box 15, Folder 21)
      - 1898-1909 (Box 15, Folder 22)
      - W. Herschel's gauges (copied by Elkin). Show to Dr. Shapley (Box 15, Folder 23)
      - 1899-1902 (Box 15, Folder 24)
      - undated (Box 15, Folder 25)
      - Lemids, 1898, 1901 (Box 15, Folder 26)
      - Geminids, 1893 (Box 15, Folder 27)
      - A I, III-VII, 1897-1899, 1905 (Box 15, Folder 28)
      - G1, 1898 (Box 15, Folder 29)
      - Lw I, II, XII-XVIII; L XVII, 1898-1904 (Box 15, Folder 30)
      - N V-X, 1898-1901 (Box 15, Folder 31)
      - OI, 1897 (Box 15, Folder 32)
      - P I-VIII, 1893-? (Box 16, Folder 33)
      - P IX XVI, XX-XXI (Box 16, Folder 34)
      - Y, 1899 (Box 16, Folder 35)
      - U.T., W, Y, 1902 (Box 16, Folder 36-37)
      - 1900-1901 (Box 16, Folder 38)
      - Notebook: Meteor Trails on Plates, 1893-1909 (Box 16, Folder 39)
      - Notebook: Meteor Formulae (Box 16, Folder 40)
      - Meteor obs. Maps, 1902(?) (Box 16, Folder 41)
      - Comparison stars for First Magnitude Parallaxes, 1875-1891 (Box 16, Folder 42)
      - Heliometer observations (Box 16, Folder 43)
  - III. Ernest William Brown, 1880-1939
    - Correspondence
      - Cowell, P.H. - Royal Observatory, Nautical Almanac Office, 1903-1919 (Box 17, Folder 1)
      - Miscellaneous, 1921, undated (Box 17, Folder 2)
      - Re: publication and distribution of Brown's work "Tables of the Motion of the Moon", 1912-1920 (Box 17, Folder 3)
      - Re: Receipt of Brown's work "Tables of the Motion of the Moon", 1920 (Box 17, Folder 4)
      - Solar eclipse, 1925 (photos included) (Box 17, Folder 5)
      - Yale University, 1917-1927 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Research notes
      - Publication notes for "Tables of the Motion of the Moon", 1913 (Box 17, Folder 7)
      - J.8. - earlier work by D.D., undated (Box 17, Folder 8)
      - J.8. - 20 terms, numerical work, undated (Box 17, Folder 9)
      - Work by C.H.D., 1923-1929 (Box 17, Folder 10)
      - First Trans Flat, undated (Box 18, Folder 11)
      - CR, tables, undated (Box 18, Folder 12)
      - undated (Box 18, Folder 13)
      - Longitude R 4, undated (Box 18, Folder 14)
      - R 1 check, undated (Box 18, Folder 15)
      - SR 1, 1918 (Box 18, Folder 16)
      - 2D +l', Hansemian Plan (2), Also interpolated to Long Cycle Plan, S 17 (18 h), 1909 (Box 18, Folder 17)
      - Long Cycle Plan, S 18 and S 19 (14 h), 1909 (Box 18, Folder 18)
      - 1911, 1916, 1917 (Box 18, Folder 19-21)
      - R 1 tables, 1918 (Box 18, Folder 22)
      - R o tables, 1912 (Box 18, Folder 23)
      - Right Ascension and Declination (Tables for Transformation to) and Auxilary, 1916 (Box 19, Folder 24)
      - S 1 Longitude, Prep. for Prints from 7-14 incl., undated (Box 19, Folder 25)
      - 1910 (Box 19, Folder 26)
      - Terms in D, 3D, 4D, 5D, 6D - Long Cycle Plan S 2' (51 h), undated (Box 19, Folder 27)
      - 2D Long Cycle Plan, S 2 (44 h), undated (Box 19, Folder 28)
      - Term in 2D-l (Long.) Long Cycle Plan S 3 (100h), undated (Box 19, Folder 29)
      - 4D - 2l. (Box 19, Folder 30)
      - 2D + l Long Cycle Plan, S 4 (21 h), 1909 (Box 19, Folder 31)
      - Term in l' (To every 0.d 1) S 5 (28 h), undated (Box 19, Folder 32)
      - 2D - l', S 6 (21 h) Hansemia Plan, 1909 (Box 19, Folder 33)
      - 2l - 2D, Long Cycle Plan, S 7 (23 h), 1909 (Box 19, Folder 34)
      - 2D - l - l', Hansemian Plan (4), S 8 (27 h) Also interpolated to long cycle plan, 1909 (Box 19, Folder 35)
      - l + l', Hansemian plan (5), S 9 (20 h), also interpolated to long cycle plan, 1909 (Box 19, Folder 36)
      - Term l, interpolation of Hansemian plan (6) Long cycle plan in cols. complete, S 10 (22h) (not including interpolation to the long cycle plan, undated (Box 19, Folder 37)
      - 2F, Long cycle plan, S 11 (39h) (Box 19, Folder 38)
      - 2F, Long cycle plan, S 12 (26 h), undated (Box 19, Folder 39)
      - Long cycle plan, S 13 (15 h), undated (Box 19, Folder 40)
      - 2F - l, Hansemia Plan (8), S 14 (7 h) not interp. to exact date, also interpolated to Long cycle plan, 1909 (Box 19, Folder 41)
      - 4D - l, Hansemian plan (1), S 15 (25 h), also interpolated to Long cycle plan, undated (Box 19, Folder 42)
      - 2D - l + l', Hansemia plan (3), S 16 (16 1/2), 1909. Now complete, April 8, 1911 (Box 19, Folder 43)
      - 4 extra S tables: 2F + 2D S 20, 2F + 2D - l S 21, 2F + 2l S 22, l + 4D S 23 (Box 19, Folder 44)
      - Parallax, 1914 (Box 19, Folder 45)
      - Longitude S.E., 2D - l', Table 23L, undated (Box 19, Folder 46)
      - S 17, Longitude S.E., 2D + l', pp. 95-97, undated (Box 20, Folder 47)
      - 25L, S 9, Longitude S.E., l + l', pp. 98-104, undated (Box 20, Folder 48)
      - S 10, Longitude S.E., l - l', pp1 105-109, undated (Box 20, Folder 49)
      - S 8, Longitude S.E., 2D - l - l', pp. 110-118 27L, undated (Box 20, Folder 50)
      - 28L, Longitude S.E., pp. 119-120, undated (Box 20, Folder 51)
      - S 16' Longitude S.E., 2D - l + l', pp. 121-127, 296, undated (Box 20, Folder 52)
      - J.8., K-sheets, Triple harmonic analysis for Î¸ terms in node, undated (Box 20, Folder 53)
      - 1913-1914 (Box 20, Folder 54-58)
      - d, Part I, l - D (Box 21, Folder 59)
      - Micrometer Screw of the Scales, Micrometer-Division Error of Scales, 1886-1887 (Box 21, Folder 60)
      - Moon's Longitude, undated (Box 21, Folder 61)
      - Latitude, undated (Box 21, Folder 62)
      - 1914 (Box 21, Folder 63)
      - Interpolation to 12th, 1917-1918 (Box 21, Folder 64)
      - "Chapter IX Construction and Continuation of the Tables p39 to p49 of Sect. VI", undated (Box 21, Folder 65)
      - Changes in constants and arguments, undated (Box 21, Folder 66)
      - Constants, undated (Box 21, Folder 67)
      - Errata, 1917 (Box 21, Folder 68)
      - Tables, undated (Box 21, Folder 69)
      - "Odds and Ends" (Box 21, Folder 70)
      - 1904 (Box 21, Folder 71)
      - Latitude, undated (Box 21, Folder 72-73)
      - Earth's and Moon's motion [and correspondence], 1903-1907 (Box 21, Folder 74)
      - "Section II: Analysis of the Errors" (Box 22, Folder 75-76)
      - Tables prep for printer, January 1915 (Box 22, Folder 77)
      - S 3, Longitude S.E., 2D - l 32L, prep for for printer, January 20-29, 1915 (Box 22, Folder 78)
      - S 2', Longitude S.E., D, 3D, 4D, 5D, 6D, prep for printer, February 20-25 (Box 22, Folder 79)
      - S 7, Longitude S.E., 2 l - 2D, 34L, prep for printer, February 25 - March 1, 1915 (Box 22, Folder 80)
      - Longitude, prep for printer, March 1-3, 1915 (Box 22, Folder 81)
      - S 3', Longitude S.E., 4D - 2l, 36L, prep for printer, March 4/one day, 1915 (Box 22, Folder 82)
      - S 15, Longitude S.E., 4D - l, 37L, prep for printer, March 5-9, 1915 (Box 22, Folder 83)
      - S 18, Longitude S.E., 30L, prep for printer, March 9-12, 1915 (Box 22, Folder 84)
      - S 23, Longitude S.E., l + 4D, 39L., prep for printer, undated (Box 22, Folder 85)
      - S 11 Longitude S.E., 2F, 40L, prep for printer, December 16-19, 1914 (Box 22, Folder 86)
      - S 12, Longitude S.E., 2F - 2D, 41L, prep for printer, December 21-28, 1914 (Box 22, Folder 87)
      - S 14, Longitude, S.E., 2F - l, prep for printer, December 28-31, 1914 (Box 22, Folder 88)
      - S 13, Longitude S.E., l + 2F, 43L, prep for printer, January 4, 1915 (Box 22, Folder 89)
      - S 20, Longitude S, E., 2F + 2D, 44L, prep for printer, January 5, 1915 (Box 22, Folder 90)
      - S 21, Longitude, S.E., 2F + 2D - l, 45L, prep for printer, January 6, 1915 (Box 22, Folder 91)
      - S 22, Longitude S.E., 2 l + 2F, also prep for printer, January 6, 1915 (Box 22, Folder 92)
      - S 5, Longitude S.E., l' 3e', 47L fin prep for printer, April 23, 1915 (Box 22, Folder 93)
      - Preparation for review of single subj. terms in new plan and other things not needed now, (1912) (Box 22, Folder 94)
      - 18h, work on tables, no longer needed, 1912 (Box 23, Folder 95)
      - Single Entry Tables, checks, undated (Box 23, Folder 96)
      - Verification of D.E. Tables (E.W.B.), 1910 (Box 23, Folder 97)
      - Verification - Double Entry Tables - Longitude, Latitude Parallax, undated (Box 23, Folder 98)
      - Longitude and Latitude Tables, undated (Box 23, Folder 99)
      - SD 1 Latitude, undated (Box 23, Folder 100)
      - Longitude D.E. 48L, undated (Box 23, Folder 101)
      - Longitude, Double Entry Table in 56 + 2F + l, Table 49 Longitude, Last of Sect. III, undated (Box 23, Folder 102)
      - Longitude terms, undated (Box 23, Folder 103)
      - Parallax, undated (Box 23, Folder 104)
      - D 6, undated (Box 23, Folder 105)
      - D 7 parallax, undated (Box 23, Folder 106)
      - D 8, undated (Box 23, Folder 107)
      - D 9 parallax, undated (Box 23, Folder 108)
      - D 10 parallax, undated (Box 23, Folder 109)
      - Longitude S.E. (?), undated (Box 23, Folder 110)
      - undated (Box 23, Folder 111)
      - 1912 (Box 24, Folder 112)
      - undated (Box 24, Folder 113)
      - CD 2 - CD 10, undated (Box 24, Folder 114)
      - D 1, undated (Box 24, Folder 115)
      - D 3, undated (Box 24, Folder 116)
      - D 4, undated (Box 24, Folder 117)
      - Difference sheets - Lunar Tables, undated (Box 24, Folder 118-119)
      - A 2 l' Part I, undated (Box 24, Folder 120)
      - A 1 Part II, undated (Box 24, Folder 121)
      - Latitude - Two Single Entry Tables in S. 2F - 2l - 2D and 2F + l and 2D + l' 17/18 Lat, undated (Box 25, Folder 122)
      - Latitude - Corrected for l' (1 - 1/803.6) Prep. for printer, April 24, 26, 1915 (Box 25, Folder 123)
      - Latitude S.E., 20 1at. to be corrected, undated (Box 25, Folder 124)
      - Prep. for printer, April 29-May 3, 1915, May 4, 1915 (Box 25, Folder 125-126)
      - 4D - F - L N 4 Latitude, undated (Box 25, Folder 127)
      - F - L N 5 Latitude - Prep. for printer, May 6, 1915 (Box 25, Folder 128)
      - F + l- 2D N3 Latitude - Prep. for printer, May 7, 1915 (Box 25, Folder 129)
      - 2D - F + l N 6 Latitude - Prep. for printer, May 10-11, 1915 (Box 25, Folder 130)
      - 2L - F N 7 Latitude - Prep for printer, May 11-12, 1915 (Box 25, Folder 131)
      - 2 l + 2D - F N 8 Latitude, Prep for printer, May 12, 1915 (Box 25, Folder 132)
      - Double entry table in N (Latitude) 29 Lat Arg. Ø,l Ø=F-2D+l6+1.u 4+c-9.u 7-0.u l0t c, undated (Box 25, Folder 133)
      - Nda 30 w 1+i(v-t), undated (Box 25, Folder 134)
      - Ndb, undated (Box 25, Folder 135)
      - Ndc 32, Latitude D.E. in N. 2D-F+I (V-T), undated (Box 25, Folder 136)
      - CD 1, Latitude D.E. l, undated (Box 25, Folder 137)
      - SD 11 Interpolated Oct. 1913, Excrm. Interpolation Dec. 1-2, 1913, Prep. for printer., December 2-5, 1913 (Box 25, Folder 138)
      - SD 12 Prep, for printer, December 4, 1913 (Box 25, Folder 139)
      - Latitude - 2 terms in S applied as additional to arg. 19 in Table 15 of Latitude (2F-l+l'), undated (Box 25, Folder 140)
      - SD 13 Latitude D.E. 2F-L 15S, Prep. for printer, December 4-6, 1913 (Box 25, Folder 141)
      - SD 14 Prep. for printer, December 6, 1913 (Box 25, Folder 142)
      - d5 2l + l' V arranged in final column Computed Jan 29, 1910 to Feb 16 Total time = 16 days (Box 25, Folder 143)
      - d 6 2l - l', undated (Box 25, Folder 144)
      - d 7 l + 2 l' VII (Box 25, Folder 145)
      - d 8 -l + 2 l' + D =, undated (Box 25, Folder 146)
      - d 9 3l + l check for only 0° to 9° of p. (Box 25, Folder 147)
      - d 10 3l - l' - 3D, undated (Box 25, Folder 148)
      - d 11 2F-2D=, undated (Box 25, Folder 149)
      - d 12 2F+l-3D, undated (Box 25, Folder 150)
      - Tables, undated (Box 26, Folder 151)
      - d'13 and d 13 2F-l d'13 is to be used instead of d 13. The term taken out to form d'13 is in a single table, undated (Box 26, Folder 152)
      - d'14 and d 14 (not to be used) 2F+2l, undated (Box 26, Folder 153)
      - d 15 2F-2l, undated (Box 26, Folder 154)
      - d 16 2F-l', undated (Box 26, Folder 155)
      - d 17 2F-l' Result not taken to safe in June 11. Put result in folder Mar 15, 1913. #'s added May 10, 1911 (Box 26, Folder 156)
      - d 18 2F+l+l', undated (Box 26, Folder 157)
      - d 19 2F-l-l', undated (Box 26, Folder 158)
      - d 20 2F+l-l', undated (Box 26, Folder 159)
      - d 21 2F-l+l', undated (Box 26, Folder 160)
      - d 22 2F+3l, undated (Box 26, Folder 161)
      - Latitude Plan, undated (Box 26, Folder 162)
      - Latitude - Principal term, Ara S, Table 33 Latitude, undated (Box 26, Folder 163)